

+44 7957 987 752 hanief@gmail.com github.com/hanief linkedin.com/in/haniefutama

Profile

I am a software developer with more than 5 years of experience in iOS and web app development. I have involved in several full lifecycle of app development: from planning, coding, testing, to publishing globally. I also have experience as a technical manager and startup founder. I am a confident leader and have excellent communication skills.

Experience

Full Stack Developer, Foresight (theforesight.co.uk); Nottingham, UK – 2017 - Present

I am the core developer team to make a modern version of their recruitment technology SaaS and take it to the next level. I am building it using PHP and Laravel on the backend, and Javascript and VueJS on the frontend. The app is used by large multinational company organizations as a critical part of their recruitment planning.

Senior iOS Developer, Qiscus (qiscus.com); Indonesia – 2015-2016

I helped the team built a chat SDK (<u>github.com/qiscus/qiscus-sdk-ios</u>) and implement it for our own chat service and several health startup clients (<u>halodok.com</u>, <u>linkdokter.com</u>, <u>apotikantar.com</u>). I built the app using Objective-C and Swift. The highlight features are: text chat, files and image attachment, video dan audio call.

As a senior developer, I trained and mentored several junior developer transitioning into iOS platform. This includes answering their questions and consulted about iOS development techniques. I ended up doubling the quantity of iOS developers at the company.

IT Manager, Poltracking (poltracking.com); Indonesia – 2014-2015

I was recruited by Poltracking, one of most prominent political consultant in Indonesia, to build backend and dashboard software to manage political polls during election day. I successfully lead a team of three to accomplish this objective. I personally built a web app using PHP and Laravel to take data input from sms sent by surveyor and process it to display as a chart display and XML feed.

Co-founder, Recomine (<u>crunchbase.com/organization/recomine</u>); Indonesia – 2013-2014

I co-founded a startup called Recomine with my friend from college. The startup received initial investment from Indigo Incubator (indigo.id). We closed it after a year because of lack of funding and traction.

I built the web app using Go at the back end and Javascript at the front end. I also managed the server infrastructure and database administration.

iOS Developer, Suitmedia (suitmedia.com); Indonesia – 2012-2013

I helped Suitmedia to build iOS apps for their clients, such as Unilever Indonesia (warisankuliner.com) for their restaurant discovery app and Bisnis Indonesia (bisnis.com) for their news reading app.

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, Universitas Gadjah Mada; Indonesia – 2009.

Languages

English, Indonesian, Objective-C, Swift, Java, Javascript, PHP, Go.

Tools

Git, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Bash, Cocoapods, TestFlight, Xcode, npm.